Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
In the previous steps, we looked at a few functional programming basics. And in this step, let's do a few
在前面的步骤中，我们看了一些函数式编程的基础知识。在这一步，让我们做一些
exercises to try and consolidate our knowledge.
练习来巩固我们的知识。
Let's start off with a simple exercise.
让我们从一个简单的练习开始。
It's to print only the odd numbers from the list.
它是只打印列表中的奇数。
So just like we have the method printEvenNumbersInListFunctional, create another method called
所以就像我们有printEvenNumbersInListFunctional这个方法一样，创建另一个方法，叫做
printOddNumbersInListFunctional.
printOddNumbersInListFunctional。
The second exercise is to print all the courses individually. Instead of using a list of integers,
第二个练习是单独打印所有的课程。而不是使用一个整数的列表、
what we are doing in here is, creating a list of String courses
我们在这里所做的是，创建一个字符串课程的列表
and we are creating a number of courses in here.
我们在这里创建了一些课程。
So, we would want to actually take this list and print each course individually on its own line by using
因此，我们希望通过使用函数式编程方法，将这个列表中的每门课程单独打印在自己的行中。
Functional programming approaches.
功能性编程方法。
The third exercise is to print courses that contain the word Spring. So, print only those courses which
第三个练习是打印包含Spring这个词的课程。所以，只打印那些
contain Spring in them.
含有Spring的课程。
The fourth exercise is to print courses whose name have at least four letters in them.
第四项练习是打印名称中至少有四个字母的课程。
You can pause the video in here and try these as an exercise. Let's get started.
你可以在这里暂停视频，把这些作为练习来尝试。让我们开始吧。
I'll go to our FP01Functional, copy it, and I'll call this FP01Exercises. And over here, what I would
我将进入我们的FP01Functional，复制它，并将此称为FP01Exercises。而在这里，我想做的是
want to do is to remove all the commented code out. So I'll remove all this stuff which is not really needed.
想做的是删除所有的注释代码。所以我将删除所有这些并不真正需要的东西。
And the only method that I'm interested in is printEvenNumbersInListFunctional.
而我唯一感兴趣的方法是printEvenNumbersInListFunctional。
Cool. We have that ready.
很好。我们已经准备好了。
What do you want to do is rename this, right click, refactor rename, print even numbers in list.
你想做的是重命名这个，右击，重构重命名，打印列表中的偶数。
Actually, we'd want to printOddNumbersInList. Right? How do I check whether something is odd? number
实际上，我们想打印OddNumbersInList。对吗？如何检查某物是否为奇数？ 数字
% 2 == 1.
So, if a number leaves a remainder of one when divided by two,
所以，如果一个数字在除以2时留下1的余数、
it's a odd number.
它就是一个奇数。
All right. So, that's basically the logic that we are using to print odd numbers.
好的。所以，这基本上就是我们用来打印奇数的逻辑。
You can also say number%2 !=0.
你也可以说number%2 !=0。
Even this code would work.
甚至这段代码也可以。
So is equal to, is equal to one or not equal to zero.
所以等于，等于一或不等于零。
Both of these logics should work.
这两种逻辑都应该是有效的。
So, I'll run this as a Java Application.
所以，我将作为一个Java应用程序运行这个程序。
Cool.
酷。
Nine, 13, 15. So only the odd numbers which are present in here are being printed out.
9、13、15。所以，只有在这里出现的奇数被打印出来了。
The second exercise was to print all courses individually.
第二个练习是单独打印所有课程。
This should be simple. Right?
这应该很简单。对吗？
So, what I'll do is, instead of creating separate methods for that, we'll actually directly write the code for it
所以，我要做的是，不要为它创建单独的方法，我们将直接在这里写代码
in here. So, I'll create a list of courses.
在这里。所以，我将创建一个课程列表。
So, if you look at these courses, they are quite a number in here.
所以，如果你看一下这些课程，它们在这里是相当多的。
So Spring, Spring Boot, API, Microservices, AWS, PCF, Azure, Docker, and Kubernetes. You can create
所以Spring、Spring Boot、API、微服务、AWS、PCF、Azure、Docker和Kubernetes。你可以创建
a list like this containing your favorite set of courses.
像这样一个包含你最喜欢的课程集的列表。
And what we'd want to do now is, we'd want to print all of them.
而我们现在想做的是，我们想把它们全部打印出来。
So, with Functional programming, the first thing that we would do is we'll convert it into a stream. And
所以，通过函数式编程，我们要做的第一件事就是把它转换成一个流。然后
for each element inside the stream,
对于流中的每个元素、
what do we want to do? First is, we would want to just print out them. So, System.out::println.
我们要做什么？首先，我们要把它们打印出来。所以，System.out::println。
Cool. Isn't it easy?
很好。这不是很简单吗？
Let's comment the earlier one. So, I'll comment
让我们评论一下前面的那个。所以，我将注释
these two lines of code and let's execute just this line of code right now.
这两行代码，我们现在只执行这一行代码。
Let's run it as Java Application and see all the courses that are being printed.
让我们把它作为Java应用程序运行，看看所有被打印的课程。
So that's Exercise 2
所以这就是练习2
done.
完成了。
Now, the Exercise 3 was to print only those courses that contain the word Spring.
现在，练习3是只打印那些包含Spring这个词的课程。
How do we do that?
我们如何做到这一点呢？
I'll copy this, paste it down,
我复制这个，粘贴下来、
comment this out, and over here what we want to do is to add a filter.
在这里，我们要做的是添加一个过滤器。
And what should be the filter?
这个过滤器应该是什么？
For every course,
对于每个课程、
only filter the course that contains the sequence Spring.
只过滤包含序列Spring的课程。
Right?
对吗？
That's what we'd want to do. Let's now try and run this, run as Java Application. Cool. Only
这就是我们想要做的。现在让我们试着运行这个，作为Java应用程序运行。酷。只有
Spring and Spring Boot are now being printed.
Spring和Spring Boot现在被打印出来了。
Now, you can pause the video in here and try the last exercise,
现在，你可以暂停这里的视频，试试最后的练习、
if you have not tried it yet. What's the last exercise? It's to print courses whose name have at least four letters.
如果你还没有尝试过。最后一个练习是什么？就是打印名称中至少有四个字母的课程。
So, courses.stream() .filter. I would want to allow only those courses which have at least four characters. So, I
所以， courses.stream() .filter. 我想只允许那些至少有四个字符的课程。所以，我
would want to eliminate AWS and PCF. How do I do that? Over here I can define course and course dot. Oops!
我想排除AWS和PCF。我如何做到这一点呢？在这里我可以定义课程和课程点。糟糕！我应该在这里使用课程！
Actually, I should use course in here;
实际上，我应该在这里使用course；
so it should not be courses. course, course.length is greater than or equal to four.
所以它不应该是course。course，course.length大于或等于4。
Now, let's run this. Awesome.
现在，让我们来运行这个。真棒。
Only six courses are being printed out. So, you can see that now we are able to filter the courses that
只有六个课程被打印出来了。所以，你可以看到，现在我们能够过滤我们想要的课程了。
we would want to have. In this quick step,
我们想拥有的课程。在这个快速步骤中、
we looked at a few exercises to implement the concepts that we have learned in the previous steps.
我们看了一些练习，以实现我们在前面步骤中学到的概念。
I'm sure you're having a lot of fun and I'll see you in the next step.
我相信你一定玩得很开心，我们在下一个步骤见。
Until then bye, bye.
在那之前，拜拜，拜拜。